本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
好了  斯坦
All right, Stan.
新的一天  身上新一处犯疼
Another day, another random body pain.
准备好了
Here we go.
亲爱的斯坦  我用了你的拖鞋装牛奶
Dear Stan, I needed something to carry milk, so I used your slippers.
爱你的梅宝
Love, Mabel.
亲爱的斯坦  灯泡被我拿去
Dear Stan, I took these
给苏斯做天象服了
to build a planetarium suit for Soos.
抱歉  迪普
Sorry! Dipper.
哎呀  还是别排在这一行了
Whoa, let's not take this line.
前面有个老头呢
There's an old person in it. Pshht!
他说不定会从包里翻出
Yeah, he's probably gonna pay with,
分币或战争债券来付款
like, pennies and war bonds.
喂  你给我听好了
Hey! For your information,
这些我大部分是打算夹带出去的
I was gonna shoplift most of this!
保安
Security!
看好了  烟雾弹
Hahh! Smoke bomb!
烟雾弹  有效期至1996年11月
逗我呢吧
Aw, seriously?
唉  今天一大早就不顺
Ahh. Rough start to a day,
但是一旦修好了灯泡
but it's all gonna be worth it
一切付出都是值得的
when I fix that light bulb.
大功告成
And we're done.
大家都看好了
Does everyone see this?
英雄就该做出这样的举动
This is what a hero looks like right here.
我还以为家里没灯泡了
I thought we were out of light bulbs.
确实没了  所以我自己发明了一个
Oh, we were. So I invented my own.
用上一千年都不会坏
It will last a thousand years,
而且灯光有嫩滑皮肤的功效
and the light it emits makes your skin softer.
从来没摸过这么顺滑的皮肤
Oh! Never have I known such softness.
总之  你刚才哪儿去了
Anyway, where were you?
懂得感激的乖电视  快用点好消息来犒劳犒劳我吧
Well, TV, at least you appreciate me. Give me the good news.
最新消息  镇长去世了
This just in: The mayor is dead.
重大新闻
-什么  -哎呀  这是怎么回事
- What?! - Whoa! What's goin' on?
在荒野中被巨熊抚养长大
Raised by bears in the wilderness,
“粗骨头”尤斯塔斯・比法弗托法普特尔镇长
Mayor Eustace "Huckabone" Befufftlefumpter
因建设本镇水塔
was best known for raising the water tower,
有可能挑起第一次世界大战
possibly starting World War I,
与将本镇流氓吉迪恩・格列佛关进
and putting town menace Gideon Gleeful behind bars--
成年人监狱而闻名
in actual adult prison.
为纪念镇长的种种功绩
A memorial statue is already being carved
效果图
镇上正在建造一座纪念雕像
in the deceased mayor's honor.
不
No!
对不起  只是太久没播报过真正的新闻了
I'm sorry. It's just been so long since we've had real news.
我喜极而泣啊
I'm just so happy!
今天中午在市政厅会有一场会议
There will be a Town Hall meeting this afternoon
决定新镇长的人选
to discuss replacing him.
新镇长
New mayor, huh?
到底谁才能当上呢
Wonder who it could be...
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
■
时间轴： WaitinZ  Enpistu
翻译： 战忽局副局座  Wizard小希  phxbe
怪诞小镇  第二季第十四集
Gravity Falls  S02E14  The Stanchurian Candidate
镇长竞选大会
■
校订  后期： Enpistu  WaitinZ
好  大家请保持安静
All right, order, everyone!
都稍安勿躁
Calm down, now.
近一个世纪以来
We're here to choose a
我们首次进行了镇长的轮换
mayor for the first time in almost a century.
根据本镇的宪章
According to the town charter,
任何血肉之躯都可以成为候选人
a worthy candidate is defined as anyone who can cast a shadow,
只要数到十  再把帽子扔到这个环里
count to ten, and throw their hat into the provided ring.
我认为我满足以上所有的条件
Well, now, I do believe I fulfill all the requirements.
-等等  巴德・格列佛  -他状态不错啊
- Wait. Bud Gleeful? - He looks good,
我们都把他儿子关起来了
considering we threw his son in jail.
那天回味无穷啊
That was a good day.
各位乡民  我知道咱们这家
Now, folks, I know our family's had
过去有点恩怨情仇啥的
its fair share of whoopsie-daisies in the past,
但是我想通过公开宣布
but I'd like to make up for it by formally announcing
我参选重力泉镇长的消息来弥补
my candidacy for the mayor of Gravity Falls!
有问题吗
Any questions?
有  你现在和小吉迪恩还联系吗
Yes. Are you still in contact with Little Gideon?
这是个好问题
That's a great question!
你买二手车我打五折
I'm giving you fifty percent off a used car.
五折  五折
Fifty percent? Fifty percent?!
事实上请大家看椅子底下
In fact, everyone look under your seats.
你买二手车打五折
You get half off a used car,
-你买二手车也打五折  -比真金白银都好
- you get half off a used car... - Better than cash!
哇  一张花里胡哨的纸  我就选他了
Wow! A colorful piece of paper! He's got my vote.
哎  对于巴德・格列佛要参选我有种不祥的预感
Guys, I've got a really bad feeling about Bud Gleeful as mayor.
我也不知道  哥们儿
I don't know, dude,
反正镇长的人选也不是很多
it's not like we have a lot of good mayor options.
小镇里的人都有点神叨叨的
Everyone in this town is a tad strange,
很讽刺的是  除了有点・神叨叨
except, ironically, Tad Strange.
大家好  我叫有点・神叨叨  但我向来都很正常
Hi, guys. Tad's the name, and being normal's my game.
爱你  阿神
Loving you, Tad!
我还喜欢面包
And I love bread.
阿福不在这儿真可惜
It's a shame Ford isn't here.
他参选肯定会胜出的
He'd run and win
他会是个好镇长
and be a great mayor.
既然大家都没意见
So, since everyone's happy,
我就宣誓就职吧
I'll just take the oath of office now,
那好  我锤了啊
sound good? Gavel up.
巴德  你给我住手
Hold it right there, Bud!
我要挑战你
I'm taking you on!
斯坦福  无意冒犯
Stanford? No offense,
但你也就是个小破坑钱老头子
but you're just some two-bit carnival barker,
而且你耳朵比脸都大
and your head is more ears than face!
是吗  好  你的脸还比不胖的人都胖
Oh, yeah? Well, your face is more fat than...not fat!
这下可好
Oh, snap.
乡亲们  我们能随随便便让巴德当选吗
What do you say, folks? Are we just gonna let Bud win?
来一次真正的选举如何
How about a real election?
把帽子扔进去啊
Get in there, hat!
乡亲们  看来竞争会很激烈嘛
Well, looks like we got some competition here, folks.
我没意见  一点意见都没有
Which I'm fine with, totally fine with.
斯坦  过去的事就算过去了
I was gonna let bygones be bygones, Stan,
但你刚刚树了个强敌
but you just made a powerful enemy.
不管怎样我都会胜出  而且我一旦胜出
I'll win either way, and when I do,
你醒来就会发现重力泉不再是天堂
you might not like the Gravity Falls you wake up in.
选举  选举  选举
Election! Election! Election!
大家嗨起来吧
Let the madness begin!
斯坦叔公  你想干嘛啊
Grunkle Stan, what are you doing?!
参选镇长啊
Running for mayor.
我  我难道没说明白
Did I-- Did I not make that clear?
斯坦叔公  不是我们觉得你选不上
Grunkle Stan, it's not that we think you can't do it,
-只是  -没关系的  梅宝  说吧
- it's just... - No, no, it's okay, Mabel.
我们觉得你选不上
We don't think you can do it.
听着  孩子们  老镇长嗝屁之后我就在思考
Look, kids, the mayor kicking the bucket got me thinking.
我这么老  也不可能回到年轻的时候
I'm an old man and I'm not getting any younger.
我那蠢兄弟的研究会让他功成名就
My dumb brother's research is probably gonna make him famous,
那我这辈子有什么好炫耀的呢
and what do I have to show for my life?
难道我真希望墓碑上刻着“投机取巧的骗子”吗
Do I really want "Crooked grifter" On my tombstone?
“投机取巧的镇长”就好多了
How about "Crooked mayor"?
来  梅宝  我们聊聊
Psst. Mabel, let's talk.
我知道斯坦不是最好的候选人
I know Stan isn't the best candidate--
而且他现在就开始偷票了
heck, he's committing voter fraud right now--
但是巴德绝对另有所图
but Bud's definitely up to something,
只有我们才能阻止他了
and we're the only ones who can stop him.
没错  迪普  再说了  斯坦魅力无穷
You're right, Dipper. Besides, Stan has a kind of charisma.
让他当选难不到哪里去
How hard could getting him elected be?
小猪猪  去拉票吧
Spread the word, pig.
好了  各位  看好了
All right, everybody, eyes up here.
重力泉的选举主要有两大事件
Okay, Gravity Falls elections are based on two events.
周三树桩演讲  在树桩上进行
the Wednesday Stump Speech, held on an actual stump,
还有周五辩论赛  小镇居民会往他们喜欢的
and the Friday Debate, wherein townsfolk throw bird seed
候选人身上扔鸟食
at the candidate they like most.
最后  他们会放出自由之鹰
At the end, they release a Freedom Eagle,
鹰会飞到鸟食最多的候选人身上
who will fly to the candidate covered in more seed
用鸟喙亲吻他的脸
and bestow a birdly kiss upon him,
授予他镇长的荣誉
anointing him mayor.
这玩意儿我编都编不出来
I couldn't make this up if I wanted to.
好 斯坦叔公
Okay, Grunkle Stan,
准备好你的首次电台采访了吗
are you ready for your first radio interview?
我不是哑巴  行了吧
I got my mouth, don't I?
好  候选人来了
Okay, you're on with the candidate.
您正在收听山泉电台
You're listening to Falls Radio,
24小时滚动播放新闻与熊伤人警告
24-hour news and bear rampage alerts.
现在有请主播T侠
And now, here's the-T Man!
您好
Hello.
候选人斯坦  第一个问题
Candidate Stan, first question:
对美国国旗您有什么看法
How do you feel about the American flag?
呃  这个老子不答白不答
Eh. I can take it or leave it.
条条杠杠太多了  下一个问题
Too many stripes. Next question?
这可不敢苟同
I don't know about that.
为了教育我们的孩子  您会怎么做
What would you do to help educate our kids?
哈  简单  扔到一个岛上
Heh! Simple. Put 'em on an island
让他们为统治权而战
and make 'em fight for dominance.
顺便教他们吐脏字
Also teach kids swears.
这样能让他们提早适应现实世界
That'll bring 'em into the real world.
对重力泉的犯罪状况有什么举措呢
What would you do about the crime in Gravity Falls?
等等  你是说大体意义上的犯罪
Wait. Do you mean crime in general,
还是说特别的犯罪  罪犯比如像我
or just the specific crimes committed by m--
好  采访结束了
Okay, interview's over.
糖糖  损失如何
Candy, what's the damage?
你的支持率原本是零
Your approval rating started at zero.
现在降到了负数
Now it's a number lower than zero.
你已经成了网络红人
You're meme-ing fast,
就是里头没一句好话
and none of them are good.
脚踏实地  迎难而上
教孩子骂娘
听着  斯坦叔公  如果把人们比作香味记号笔
Look, Grunkle Stan,people are like smell markers,
你的味道就是黑色甘草糖
and you're black licorice.
不好闻并不是你的错
It's not that you're unsniffable,
只是要在必要的时候把笔帽盖上
you just need to learn when to keep the cap on.
从现在开始  你还是读我们给你准备好的发言吧
From now on,maybe you should just read our prepared remarks.
哈哈  抱歉了  孩子们
Heh heh! Sorry, kids.
我向来想到什么就直说
I only say words that come out of my brain.
要是我觉得一个女人抱的孩子很丑
If my head says,"That lady's got an ugly baby,"
我嘴上就会直说“天呐  女士  您的孩子真丑”
my mouth says, "Whoa, lady!You got one ugly baby!"
他非要说自己想说的话
And he's insisting on speaking his mind!
这么说这确实是个紧急情况
So this is an emergency.
再过几天就要做树桩演讲了
The Stump Speech is in a couple of days,
他要是继续这样的话  我们就必败无疑了
and if he continues like this,we'll lose to Bud for sure.
没有那种可以控制别人的装置
Hmm. It's a shame there isn't some device
实在是太可惜了
that would allow you to control someone else.
哦  等一下  还真有
Oh, wait. Of course.
没错  就是这个
Yes. There is.
很久以前我给里根总统的主人们
A long time ago I designed a prototype
设计过一个原型
for Ronald Reagan's masters.
只要让斯坦带上这个
just get stan to wear this
他就能逐字逐句地重复你说的话
and you can make him a literal talking head.
哇噻  简直太赞了
Whoa! This is amazing!
从伦理角度来讲也没啥无可厚非的
And ethically ambiguous!
只要你戴这条配对的
As long as you wear the matching one,
他就会和你说一样的话
he'll say and do whatever you want him to.
谢谢  阿福叔公
Thank you, Great Uncle Ford!
行了行了  用的时候负点责任啥的
Yes, yes. Use it responsibly and all.
哇  伙计们  谢谢你们送的瘦身领带
Whoa, thanks for the slammin' tie, dudes.
这些条纹真的很显瘦
These stripes are so slimming.
你真觉得这个控制大脑的领带会管用吗
You really think this mind control tie is gonna work?
打开开关我们试试
Flip the switch and test it out.
嗷嗷嗷  我是热舞小子
Oh oh oh,I'm a dancing dude
我坏坏的却舞技高超
I got the fancy moves and a bad attitude
哈  简直太棒了
Ha! That's amazing!
伙计们  刚才出怪事了
Guys! Something weird just happened.
吓死我了
I'm really freaked out
我是苏大胖  看我吃松球
I am Soos-tron. Watch me eat this pinecone.
思想控制什么的简直太棒了
Mind control is <i>awesome!</i>
天啊
Oh, my gosh!
我的一生刚刚从眼前闪过
My life just flashed before my eyes! Ohh!
教育  触手可得
Education? Git it!
繁荣  触手可得
Prosperity? Git it!
一个我们引以为傲的重力泉
A Gravity Falls we can be proud of?
也将触手可得
Git <i>it!!!</i>
我非得戴这个领带吗
Do I really have to wear this thing?
看着就像一面旗在我身上吐了似的
It looks like a flag threw up on me.
斯坦叔公  你就相信你的幸运领带吧
Grunkle Stan,just trust your lucky tie.
接下来有请  斯坦福・派恩斯
And now, Stanford Pines!
到你了  斯坦叔公
You're on, Grunkle Stan!
这样  只有他搞砸了的时候咱们才插手
Okay, we'll only jump in if he starts doing badly.
大家好  我是斯坦・派恩斯
Hiya there! Stan Pines here.
咱们说点正经事吧  难道你们不觉得重力泉的女人
Let's get real. Do you thinkthe women of Gravity Falls
化妆品用得太多吗
wear too much makeup?
插手  快插手
Jump in! Jump in!
呃  其实我想说的是
Uhh! Uh,what I  meant  to say was,
你们这些女士们看起来都漂亮极了
you ladies all look great.
你是不是做了头发
And have you done something with your hair?
姐妹们  真的很好看哦
Girl, you are workin' it!
这正是我现在想听的话啊
That is exactly what I needed to hear right now!
我是斯坦・派恩斯
I'm Stan Pines.
你们认识我可能是因为我几年前上小学的时候
You may know me as that guy who accidentally let all those bees loose
不小心捅了个马蜂窝
in that elementary school a few years back.
我是一个有信仰的人
But I believe in things.
美国  自由
America. Freedom.
自由之美
Amerifreedom.
太好了  他说的都是对的
Good. He's saying all the right things.
正如我的对手所说
Like my opponent pointed out,
虽然我颜值不高
I may not have a pretty face,
但如果你们想要一个善于倾听民意的候选人的话
but if you want a candidate that will listen to you,
我愿意竖起耳朵倾听你们的心声
well, I'm proud to be all ears.
现在来看我的收场表演吧
Now watch me break it <i>down!</i>
斯坦叔公  您刚才的演讲太棒了
Grunkle Stan,that was amazing!
派恩斯先生  您是怎么做到的
Yeah! How'd you do it, Mr. Pines?
呃  这个我也不知道
Uh, I don't know.
我就是张开嘴  用心演讲
I just opened my mouth and spoke from the heart.
或者用肺腑什么的
Or gut. Or something.
那是什么声音
What is that sound?
为什么人们要把两只手放在一起拍来拍去的
Why are people jamming their hands together?
那叫鼓掌
It's applause!
斯坦叔公  他们很爱你
Grunkle Stan,they love you!
他们爱我
They... <i>love </i> me?
斯坦  斯坦  斯坦
Stan! Stan! Stan!
他来了  派恩斯先生  能拍个照片吗
There he is! Mr. Pines, can we get a picture?
斯坦必胜
Yes we Stan!
本地伐木工一致推选斯坦
深得老年人心
承诺施行新草坪法案
斯坦获得海狸支持
各位  看谁是落水狗
斯坦・派恩斯上位领跑
真该死
Doggone it!
见他的可爱甜蜜的鬼去吧
Gosh heck huckleberry honeysuckle darn it!
原谅我说的粗话  真的很抱歉
Excuse my language.I'm so sorry.
哦  这下完了  真完了
Oh, this is bad.This is  <i>real </i> bad.
我要跟我的竞选经纪人说几句话
I need to speak with my campaign manager.
失陪一会儿
Please excuse me for a moment.
事情变成这样  我真的很抱歉
Look, I'm sorry about all this.
虽然有点小挫折  但是我们一定会赢的
This is a minor setback,but we'll win,
我有信心
I'm sure of it.
小挫折
Minor setback?
你管这叫小挫折
Minor setback?!
你听着  老爹  你给我听好了
You listen, Daddy,and you listen good.
监狱生活简直就是噩梦
Prison is a nightmare!
我日复一日地吃着同样的稀饭
I eat the same slop every day!
他们这里没有护发产品
They have no hair products in here!
我没法睡觉  因为我的狱友拿我的枕头当老婆
I can't sleep because my cellmate took my pillow for a wife!
你觉得我在这儿呆着很好玩吗
You think I've been having fun in here?!
嗨  好基友  待会儿的友谊手链编织课可不要迟到哦
Hey, best friend! Don't be late for Friendship Bracelet class!
那个时间我有手指画课
I have fingerpainting at the same time!
镇长死了是我唯一逃出去的机会
The mayor dying's my one ticket out of here,
正因为这个你才非赢了这次选举不可
which is why you're gonna win this election,
把我从监狱里救出来  这次绝不能再让派恩斯家的人
pardon me out of prison, and we're not gonna let the Pines
耽误我的好事了
get in my way again!
但是  但是你不明白
But-- but you don't understand.
他在竞选中做得很出色  就像有魔法一样
He's going great in the polls.It's almost like magic.
你是说魔法咯
Magic, you say.
这么说  也许是时候以毒攻毒了
Well, maybe it's time we fight fire with fire.
这个咒语我已经留了很久了
I been saving this for a long time,
终于能派上用场了
waiting for the right moment.
儿子  听着  咱们不是说好了吗
Boy, now, we discussed this.
不许再用那些歪门邪道的咒语了
No more spooky spells.
我说老爹
Well, Daddy,
也许您的头脑需要再开放些了
maybe you just need to have more of an open mind.
不要  儿子  别这样
No, boy, not that!
只要别念咒语啥都行
Anything but that!
选举日
他来了
Ooh, it's him!
很帅嘛  候选镇长
Lookin' good,mayor candidate.
我就要给这家伙投票
Hooeey! It's the guy I'm gonna vote for!
很帅哦  斯坦  真不错
Lookin' A-OK, Stanford, A-OK.
阿神  你的鼓励对我来说很重要
Tad, that means so much coming from you.
大家好
Hey-O!
斯坦
Stan!
所有女士一起来
Now just the ladies.
斯坦
Stan!
和我年龄相仿的女士们
Now just the ladies my age.
斯坦
Stan!
还是算了
Never mind.
算小店请客  大人物先生
On the house, Mr. Big Shot.
这个我很快就能适应
Now, this I could get used to.
斯坦叔公  你怎么穿这件外衣了
Grunkle Stan,what's with the outfit?
你忘戴你的幸运领带了
You're missing your lucky tie.
超能领带  必须得戴
Power tie.Gotta wear it.
得了吧  你们难道没看见我在竞选时的表现吗
Come on,have you seen the polls?
我不穿衣服演讲都能赢
I could debate naked and I'd still win.
咦  这倒真是个不错的主意
Huh. Come to think of it...
哈哈  不过说真的
Ha ha. Seriously, though,
你必须要穿那套西装打领带  斯坦叔公
we need you to wear that suit and tie, Grunkle Stan.
西装领带  必须得穿
Suit and tie. Gotta wear it.
真是的  你们这俩小孩干嘛总对我指手画脚的
Uhh! Why do you kids have to constantly tell me what to do?
镇子里的人终于开始尊敬我了
Everyone in this town is finally showing me respect--
你们俩也应该这样
maybe you kids should, too.
斯坦叔公  只要你能再重视点这件事
Grunkle Stan, we'd respect you
我们肯定尊重你
if you took things more seriously.
我确实是很严肃地对待这件事
I am taking this seriously!
也许你没注意到
If you haven't notice
正是我的金口玉言  让我们取得了这样的成功
everything that's coming out of this golden mouth has put us on top,
有没有你们的蠢主意都一样
with without your dumb advice!
蠢主意
Dumb advice?!
没错  就是蠢主意
Yeah! Dumb advice.
见鬼  斯坦
Dang it, Stan!
你的每一场演讲都是我们操控你说出来的
Every one of those speeches we were controlling you!
-迪普  -你说啥
-Dipper!  -What?!
这条领带是阿福发明的头脑控制装置
This tie is a mind control device invented by Ford.
要是没有这条领带  你不可能会赢
If it wasn't for this tie, you'd be losing!
你去告诉那个万事通阿福
Well, you can tell that know-it-all Ford
没有他花哨的灯泡和魔力领带
that he can keep his fancy light bulbs and magic ties.
我自己照样能赢  不用你们帮忙
I'm gonna win this debateon my own,without any of you!
斯坦  等等  别走
Stan, wait! You can't!
哦  这下糟了
Oh, this is bad.
要是我们还想打败巴德  就必须快点找一个新的竞选人
If we want to beat Bud, we need another candidate, fast.
我们需要一个没主见的人
What we need is a blank slate,
一个什么话都能听进去的人
someone totally suggestible,
一个可塑性强  任我们摆布的人
an empty piece of clay we can mold to our whims.
伙计们  帮我个小忙
Hey, a little help,dudes?
我不小心把头卡在袖子里
I accidentally got my head stuck in my shirt sleeve.
可能一时半会儿是取不出来了
I guess this is my life now.
选举专用鸟食出售
Seed here!
把鸟食投给你最青睐的镇长候选人吧
Support your favorite candidate by throwing election seed!
欢迎各位收看本次竞选的最终辩论
Welcome, all, to the final debate
即使这一事件从人类历史宇宙洪荒的视角看
in what's sure to be, on a cosmic scale,
无疑毫不起眼  终将被人遗忘
a forgettable blip in human history.
现在登场的是人气最高的三位候选者
And here come the three more popular candidates!
噢  你好哇  斯坦福
Oh! Hello there, Stanford.
一日不见如隔三秋呀
Long time no see. Hee hee. Whoo-hoo-hoo!
别跟我嬉皮笑脸的  等着在辩论赛上战个痛快吧
Don't you "Tee-hee" Me. I'll debate you into the ground!
是吗  我可有着招人喜欢的甜蜜小酒窝呢
Oh, but I have a widdle twick up my sweevie-weeves.
我真要被你恶心哭了
You're making me very uncomfortable right now.
现场出了新状况
But what's this?
又有一位候选人加入了这次的辩论赛
One new candidate has entered the race!
等等  这是什么意思
Wait a minute. What?!
忘恩负义的小崽子们
Those backstabbing...
现在辩论开始
Let the debate begin!
第一个问题
First question:
你们在斧头问题上的立场是什么
What's your position on axes?
啊  我说错了  是税收问题
Wait. I mean... taxes.
这很简单  税收是罪恶
Easy. Taxes are the worst.
我的信念是通过向周边城镇
I propose we stimulate the economy
发动战争来刺激经济发展
by waging wars on neighboring cities.
我们需要开炮
We have the cannons.
啊  这
What? Uh...
我不能说对于税收有很深刻的见解
I don't know much about taxes,
但我承诺每家每户的锅里都将有一只小猫
but I can promise you a kitten in every pot.
你在说些什么鬼话  梅宝
That doesn't make sense, Mabel.
你说的才是鬼话呢  迪普
You don't make sense, Dipper!
胖友们  胖友们  你们明白现在场上是什么状况吗
Fwends. Fwends. Can't you see what's happening on this stage?
这些政客们在回避你们的问题呢
These politicians are dancing around the issues.
而我  可以用歌声来回答你们
Well, I can sing round the issues!
犯罪是过错  大错又特错
Crime is bad, crime is so, so bad
巴德当镇长  罪恶扫光光
Vote for Bud and it ain't gonna be no crime
犯罪是大错  投票给巴德
Crime's bad. Vote for Bud
选民们可以开始用鸟食投票了
You may now throw your birdseed.
接下来是中场休息时间
And now a quick intermission.
我们眼看就要输掉辩论了
We're getting eaten alive back there.
奇怪  巴德什么时候变得这么讨喜了
Since when has Bud been creepily adorable?
我怎么知道  这说不通啊
I don't know! It doesn't make sense!
他的举止简直就像  就像
He's almost acting just like... like...
小小的我
Widdle old me.
啊哈  你们好呀  好久不见
Aha! Hello there! Long time no see.
虽然我每隔一小时就会在
Except in my revenge fantasies
我的复仇之梦里见到你们
where I see you on an hourly basis.
吉迪恩  我就知道是你在背后搞的鬼
Gideon! I knew you were somehow behind this!
是你一直在操纵巴德
You've been controlling Bud!
你们不也在悄悄操纵着斯坦福吗
And it seems you've been controlling Stanford!
在下不得不佩服你俩
I have to hand it to both y'all.
和上次见面的时候相比  你们可学坏了不少哇
You've gotten much eviler since I last saw ya.
老爹
Daddy.
放开我们
Let go of us!
等着看接下来的精彩辩论吧
Behold your grand view of the debate!
只要搞定这次选举
Once I win this election,
我就能统治整个破小镇了
I'll finally rule this backwoods town!
你不可能有好下场的  你这小怪胎
You'll never get away with this, you creepy little dork!
梅宝  我还想着或许能放过你呢
Oh, I'd be happy to spare you, Mabel--
只要你答应嫁给我
if you agree to be mine.
我甚至为你亲手缝制了这件婚纱
I even made you this wedding dress in crafts class.
你不会想知道这是用什么做的
Don't ask what it's made of.
我死也不跟你在一起  变态
Ew! I'd rather die, you creep!
那行吧  随便你  只要我赢了
Fine! Have it your way. Once I win,
他们就会启动这个按钮  制造烟花效果来庆祝
they'll hit the plunger for the fireworks display,
同时引爆整座镇长雕塑的山体
finishing the mountain's construction,
把你们都送上西天
trapping you all inside.
整个夏天我都在铁窗后饱受囹圄之苦
I've been trapped behind concrete all summer--
现在轮到你们了
now see how you like it!
和重力泉的新镇长问个好吧  孩子们
Say hello to the next mayor of Gravity Falls, kids!
这就是为什么  嗯
And that is why, um,
自由女神像会成为最性感火爆的地标
the Statue of Liberty is our hottest landmark.
好吧  我胡说的  她其实是个男人婆
Awright, I lied. She's kind of mannish.
观众支持率
你们还想怎么样
What do you want from me?
你是快完蛋了  斯坦
Ahh. You're dying out there, Stan.
孩子们  你们一直是对的
Kids, you were right all along.
我就该乖乖听你们的  我早干嘛去了
I shoulda listened to you when I had the chance.
救命  救救我们  什么
Help! Help us! What the--?!
我们被绑在烟花的炸药上了
We're tied to a bunch of fireworks!
孩子们
Kids!
大家听好了
Listen, everybody,
辩论结束
this debate is over.
我得马上去救我的家人
I gotta go save my family!
大家别理他们  他们只是喜欢拆台的熊孩子
No, those--those are just some demolition dummies.
没什么好看的
Nothin' to see here.
闭嘴  格列佛
Can it, Gleeful!
在这个惊人的插曲中
In a shocking turn of events,
斯坦・派恩斯已经冲向了两个命悬一线
Stan Pines has run to the aid of two children
急待救援的孩子
who appear to be in danger.
他的英勇赢得了市民们的心
And the crowd is loving it!
不  住手  谢了  别再拿鸟食扔我了
No! Stop it! Thank you, but stop it!
滚开  你们这群丑鸟
Get back, you terror birds!
斯坦叔公
Grunkle Stan!
孩子们  听着  是我一直顽固不化  抱歉
Kids! Look, I'm sorry I was being stubborn.
我不想再人们面前逞英雄了
I guess being the town's
那远远不够  我想当守护你们的英雄
hero wasn't enough-- I wanted to be yours, too.
是我们不对  斯坦叔公
We're sorry, Grunkle Stan.
我们本应该一直站在你这边  不论输赢
We should have supported you, win or lose.
多半是输
Probably lose.
放明白点  我现在还可以放手
I can still drop you, you know.
不不不不不不不不  又是这样
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, not again!
是时候一了百了了
Time to take care of you once and for all!
哦不  我们得逃出去
Oh no! We have to get out of here!
万一我这下牺牲了
Kids, if I die,
你们一定要把我的墓碑建得比阿福的气派
make sure I get a bigger tombstone than Ford.
不不
No! No!
派恩斯镇长  派恩斯镇长  派恩斯镇长
Mayor Pines! Mayor Pines! Mayor Pines!
看来胜负已经见分晓了
Well, I guess we know who won.
最新消息
This just in:
斯坦福・派恩斯落选
Stanford Pines loses.
失去资格
在投票环节获得了百分之九十五的压倒性胜利之后
Despite winning an overwhelming 95% of the vote,
他因为其各种各样的犯罪案底
election officials had to disqualify him
被选举委员会剥夺竞选资格
due to discovery of an extensive criminal record.
我的天
Oh boy.
斯坦  你又闯什么祸了
Stan, what did you do?
我什么祸没闯过
What didn't I do?
包括盗窃的各项犯罪记录
Crimes include shoplifting,
他还自创了一种名叫“盗贪罪”的新型犯罪
a new crime he invented called "Burgle-bezzlement,"
对羊驼的谋杀重罪
first-degree llamacide...
那只羊驼知道的太多了
That llama knew too much.
这出人意料的事态发展
Due to this shocking development,
使镇长一职自然而然地落到了本次竞选
it would appear the mayorship passes to
唯一符合各项文件要求的竞选人身上  也就是
the only candidate who actually filled our their paperwork,
本市的热心活动家  泰勒・尊可爱的身上
local enthusiasm enthusiast Tyler Cutebiker.
拿下
Got it.
本节目接下来的主要内容
We will dedicate the rest of this broadcast
是列举斯坦的各项罪行
to listing Stan's crimes.
重罪  盗窃体温计  非法贩卖哈巴狗
First-degree thermometer theft, pug trafficking--
呼  幸好他们曝光的都是些鸡毛蒜皮的事儿
Whoo! At least they didn't list any of the bad ones.
话说回来  我这里还有很多便宜的哈巴狗
On an unrelated topic, I have a lot of cheap pugs,
得快点转手出去才行
and I need to move them fast.
我很遗憾  斯坦
I'm sorry, Stan.
我还有点期待你当镇长的样子呢
I actually think you as mayor would have been fun.
那样当然好啦
Maybe it's for the best.
但我这次离目标也很近了嘛  孩子们
I got close the dream, though, kids.
嘿  我给你织了个东西哦
Hey, I knit you something.
不代表官方意见  但也还算应景喽
It's not official, but I think it fits.
我们的英雄
斯坦叔公  你不会在哭吧
Grunkle Stan, are you crying?
只是彩纸屑飘到眼睛里罢了
I got campaign confetti in my eyes.
好了孩子们  想去泰勒镇长的官邸里搞点破坏吗
Come on, kids, want to go vandalize Mayor Tyler's mansion?
-搞破坏  -耶
- Hey hey! Vandalism! - Yay!!!
真遗憾你的选举计划最后还是泡汤了  老弟
I'm sorry the election thing didn't work out for you, bro.
如果这样你会好受点的话
If it makes you feel any better,
我们可以计划一下今晚的暴乱
we're gonna throw a riot tonight.
想来一次暴乱么
Does someone want to throw a riot?
谢啦  鬼眼  我没那个心情
Thanks, Ghost Eyes, I'm just not in the mood.
这张海报是支撑我的全部动力
This poster is the only thing keeping me going.
喵喵撑住别倒下
这次我终于痛下决心达成交易了
I'm finally ready to make a deal.